孩子们 2013年春天
Kids, in the spring of 2013,
2030年
在那场重大婚礼前 我们都在处理一些余留的问题
we were all tying up loose ends before the big wedding.
我正是在这个房间里
I was right here in this very room,
给房子装修画上句号
putting the finishing touches on the house.
饶了我吧
Oh, come on!
巴尼和罗宾都已经快排练好
Barney and Robin were wrapping up rehearsal
他们跳的第一支舞了
for their first dance.
那真太棒了 我们可以做得更好
That was amazing. We can do better.
从头开始 各位
Back to one, everyone!
重新装好炮弹 我们准备再来一次
Reload the cannons, we'll go again right away.
莉莉和马修正忙着打包行李
And Lily and Marshall were packing
准备去意大利工作生活一年
for their year in Italy.
喂
Hello.
我的宝贝儿媳妇怎么样啊
How's my favorite daughter-in-law?
呃 事情有点多
Oh, things are a bit crazy here.
我们正准备举家搬到罗马
We've got this big move to Rome coming up,
而且 我一直觉得
and I, I just can't shake the feeling
我好像忘带了什么
that I'm forgetting something, you know.
我懂 我懂 我是有点不正常了 是吧
I know, I know, I'm being crazy, right?
是吧 朱迪
Right, Judy?
你们居然要搬去罗马
You're moving to Rome?!
是我妈妈吗
Is that my mom?
别提罗马
Don't mention Rome.
老爸\N　　　  　　 老妈\N　　 　　 浪漫史\N　　  　　　　第八季  第二十四集\N
S08E24 Something New
翻译: @卟哒哒伽马 @麟礡 @阿狸小H @moonywen文妹\N@KRengine达 @Big-Fudge @纷扬DLL @Mr_Gao703 @@KRengine达\N校对: @我叫肉鸭鸭 @晒小花
校对: @麟礡 @阿狸小H\N压制: @Big-Fudge\N统筹+后期: 相约九月肉小鸭 下季再见晒小花
HIMYM字幕组 倾情奉献
你没有跟你老妈说要去罗马的事啊
You didn't tell your mom about Rome?
感觉不太合适吧
It didn't feel right.
这消息不应该在电话上说啊
This isn't over-the-phone news.
必须得当面说才行
This is face-to-face news.
所以我准备到了圣诞节见面的时候再告诉她
I was gonna tell her when we see her at Christmas.
你准备一直等到
You were gonna wait and tell her
我们都搬去住了六个月了再告诉她吗
after we had already been living there for six months?
那...可真是一个好主意啊
That... was a great plan.
喵的
Damn it.
喂 麻麻 我是马修
Hey, Mom, it's Marshall.
如果你们真要搬去罗马
If you're moving to Rome,
我起码得在你们走之前见见我孙子
I at least need to see my grandson before you go!
那是自然 所以呢 我们很乐意
Of course, and that is why we would love
让您来我们这住上一个星期
for you to come visit us for a week.
不行
No.
这地方都已经打包好了
The place will be all packed up.
哦 好吧 对了 老妈 有个更好的主意
Oh, oh, uh, okay, hey, Mom, better idea:
要不我们一起上你那儿住一个星期怎么样
how about we all come visit you for a week?
我没法去明尼苏达待一个星期啊
I can't go to Minnesota for a week.
我得上班
I have a job.
好吧 老妈 是这样的 莉莉得上班
Okay, Mom, here's the plan: um, Lily has to work,
所以我和马尔文去你那儿待一个星期
so Marvin and I will come visit you for a whole week,
我看看能不能赶上下一班飞机
and I-I'll see if I can get a last-minute flight.
你要把我襁褓中的宝贝儿子
You are going to take my infant son
从我身边带走 整整一个星期吗
away from me for a whole week?
呜哈
Whoo!
你今晚想要干嘛
So, what do you want to do tonight--
喝到看不清路 还是放火烧掉一辆车
drink ourselves blind, set a car on fire?
或者看一个电影
Ooh, watch a movie that doesn't start
开头不是一盏台灯跳到大写字母I上的那种
with a desk lamp jumping on top of a capital "I"?
皮克斯动画出品电影经典开头
我都听你的啦 西区泰迪
I'm all yours, Teddy Westside.
其实呢 今晚我叫泰迪•西区切斯特吧
Actually, tonight it's Teddy Westchester.
我得去我的房子那边 再修整一些东西
Got to head up to the house, take care of some stuff.
噢 对哦 房子修的怎么样了
Oh, yeah, how's the restoration going?
事实上 搞定了
Actually, done.
已经完工了吗
You finished the house?
我要去看看
Well, I want to see it.
马修已经把网断了 是吗
Marshall already canceled the cable, huh?
连无线也没有了
And the Wi-Fi.
就像住在那该死的草原上的小木屋里一样
It's like Little House on the Freaking Prairie up there.
草原上的小木屋 美国经典童话名著
好了 婚礼也计划完毕
Well, the wedding planning is done,
今晚呢 完全是用来放松并庆祝我们的一切不凡
so tonight is all about relaxing and celebrating everything that makes us awesome,
所以我呢
which is why
特意要了那张我们最喜欢的那个位子
I requested our favorite table.
靠窗的那个
The one by the window.
在那里 我们观赏了两个流浪汉的彻夜激斗
Where we were sitting the night we saw those two bums fighting.
为了一个三明治
Over a sandwich.
我们都快要叫警察了
We almost called the cops.
然后我们突然意识到 是我们会错意了
And then we realized they weren't fighting at all.
他们在进行爱之激斗
They were making love.
在一个三明治上
Over a sandwich.
噢 我差点忘了
Oh, I almost forgot.
不会吧 这不是
Ha-ha, yeah. No way, is that...?
金字塔
El Piramide.
S01E14中 蒙特二号 也叫鱼雷 BR一起抽的第一支雪茄
我们一起抽的第一支雪茄
The first cigar we ever smoked together.
噢 巴尼
Aw, Barney.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你们好
Hi.
你们能不能 别... 谢谢
Could you not? Thanks.
老兄 我又不会在这点上
dude, I'm not gonna light 'em up in here.
我就是看看罢了
I'm just looking at 'em.
是啊 但是即使没有点上
Right, but even when they're unlit,
这味道也很...
the smell-- it's very...
冲鼻子
Pungent.
完全正确 谢谢
Exactly-- thank you.
这气味非常冲鼻子
It's a very pungent smell.
所以 你们能不能别...
So, could you not?
再谢谢啊
Thanks.
好
Okay.
不好意思 能把袋子也拿开吗
I'm sorry, can you also put the bag away?
这个看着实在倒胃口
It-It's just really unappetizing to look at.
你个死光头才倒胃口嘞
You're unappetizing to look at.
好了好了 我把雪茄拿开 好吧
You know what? Um, I'll put them away, okay?
祝你们有个愉快的夜晚
Enjoy your night.
我们尽量愉快吧
We'll try.
这两只现在变成我们的死敌了
Did those two just become our archenemies?
不 罗宾 他们一直是我们的死对头
No, Robin, they've always been our archenemies.
只是刚刚暴露而已
They've only just revealed themselves.
嗨 克里斯汀
Hi, Kristen?
每个人都读错
Everyone pronounces it wrong.
R在I后面
The "R" Is after the "I""
克尔斯汀
Kirsten.
I前面还有一个R呢
And before the "I""
是克里耳屎汀
It's Krirsten.
您的桌子好了
Your table's ready.
哇 他们还真混里个蛋
Wow, they're "Trerrible""
听我说
You know what?
不要去想他们 好吗
Don't even think about them, okay?
-今晚我们是来庆祝的  -你是对的
-Tonight is about celebrating us. -You're right, you're right.
-我们不应该让另外一对  -不行 绝对不行
-We shouldn't let a couple... -Nope, nope.
我是一名自封的幽闭恐惧症患者
I'm a self-diagnosed claustrophobic.
我必须要坐在窗户边
I have to sit next to the window.
不要 那是我们的桌子×3
No, that's our table, that's our table,that's our table,
那是我们的桌子×3
that's our table, that's our table, that's our table,
你知道吗
You know what?
去他妹的庆祝咱俩 知道咱们该怎么做吗
Screw celebrating us. You know what we're gonna do?
让那俩得意又烦人的狗娘养的付出代价×2
Make those smug, obnoxious sons of bitches pay.
啊呜
Aw...
莉莉阿姨和我开车去了西区特切斯特
So Aunt Lily and I drove up to Westchester.
西区特切斯特 泰德房子所在地 详见S05E20
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby,
明尼苏达那边情况怎么样
how's Minnesota?
简直太有趣了
It is so much fun.
等一会儿
Oh, hold on one sec.
马修 我专门为你做了欢迎回家的冰淇淋圣代
Marshall, I made you this welcome-home ice cream sundae.
但是我不记得 你喜欢碎果仁吗
But I can't remember, do you like crushed nuts?
别 别
no, no
我超爱碎果仁
I love crushed nuts.
crush有打碎的意思 nut又有蛋蛋的意思
哦
Oh!
总之 回到家真是太好了
Anyway, it's, it's great to be home.
朱迪还好吧
How's Judy doing?
她很好
Oh, she's great.
很有意思 知道吗 她一直在开玩笑说
It's cute, you know, she keeps joking
她多么不想让我们离开
about how she's not gonna let us leave.
我真没有
I'm really not.
这不是玩笑哦
It's not a joke.
朱迪还跟他说要一起去罗马呢
Judy's going to talk him out of going to Rome.
我就知道会有事情搅和我们的计划
I knew something was going to screw up our plans,
就是这事
and this is it.
她肯定会说服他永远不要离开这里的
She is going to convince him never to leave the country.
我觉得你可能想多了
I think you're imagining things.
哦 是吗 看看她发在脸书上的东西
Oh, yeah? Well, check out what's already on Facebook.
大美利坚
没有说服力
Inconclusive.
真的吗
Oh, really?
罗马弱爆
现在有点说服力了
It's getting conclusiver.
嘿 莉莉
Hey, Lily.
-怎么  -跟我来
-What? -Come on.
好了 张开吧
Okay, open'em.
你的眼睛 对不起 你应该闭上眼睛的
Your eyes-- sorry, they should have been closed.
这得怪我
That one's on me.
我们再试一次
Let's try again.
哇哦
Wow.
泰德 这些都是你一个人做的吗
Ted, you did this all yourself?
就像恋恋笔记本中的瑞恩•高斯林那样
Just like Ryan Gosling in The Notebook.
瑞恩•高斯林 加拿大演员
我今天一直很男人 直到我提到
I was pretty manly till I mentioned
恋恋笔记本中的瑞恩•高斯林 对吧
Ryan Gosling in The Notebook, huh?
连我都没看过这部电影 泰德
Even I haven't seen it, Ted.
想象一下吧 你的孩子们
Just think, this is the house
会在这间房子里长大
your kids are going to grow up in.
他们会在这个壁炉里烤棉花糖
They are going to roast marshmallows in this fireplace.
他们会在前庭那边
They're gonna experiment
尝尝快活小丸丸
with recreational drugs on that porch.
他们会坐在放在这里的沙发上
They're gonna sit on a couch right here
听你讲那些无聊的故事 关于
and listen to your boring stories about...
"待售"牌
"For sale" Sign?
你要把这间房子卖了吗
Are you selling this place?
是啊
Yeah.
为什么啊
Why?
因为我要搬去芝加哥
Because I'm moving to Chicago.
嗷
Ow.
那 我们要怎么弄
So, what are we gonna do--
在他们吃的东西里加点料
put something in their food,
在他们车子上划几道 噢
key their car? Ooh,
你的雪茄里面有会爆炸的那种吗
do either of those cigars explode?
悠着点 大野狼 我想到一个好点子
Hold on, Wile E. Coyote, I think I got something.
来源于动画《哔哔鸟和大野狼》
他在打量那个迎宾员
He's checking out the hostess.
正处于欢快约会中的男人用这样的眼光偷瞄
Now, a guy who's happily in a relationship sees a girl
别的女人的话 他偷瞄的次数将可达14-15次
like that, he'll check her out maybe 14, 15 times, tops.
16次 封顶了
16 times, tops.
这么说 克里耳屎汀在这段关系里比她奸夫
So Krirsten's more invested in the relationship
要投入的多啊
than her fella is.
这可以用来大做文章
That could spell trouble.
接受挑战
Challenge accepted.
嘿 你说一个新娘在她婚礼之前
Hey, do you think it's bad luck for a bride
把一对陌生人给拆散了会不会有点败人品啊
to break up two strangers a week before her wedding?
我说这相当败人品啊...败克里耳屎汀的人品
I'd say it's very bad luck... for Krirsten.
噢 我恨死这桌子了
Ow, I hate this table so much!
你为什么要搬去芝加哥啊
Why would you move to Chicago?
因为那儿是我的完美之城
Because it's the perfect town for me.
它像是克利夫兰化的纽约
I-It's like a Clevelandy New York,
而且 不知道你有没有注意到
and-- don't act like you haven't noticed--
我的头发风中凌乱时特别好看
my hair excels in the wind.
芝加哥外号风城 常年大风
另外
Besides,
你们也搬去罗马了
you're moving to Rome.
但是只去一年啊 而且等我们回来时
Yeah, for a year, a-and when we get back,
需要看到你在这儿等着我们啊
we need you to be here waiting for us,
没准是和你未来的新娘生活在这间房子里
hopefully living in this house with your future bride.
什么...什么未来的新娘
Wha... what future bride?
那个女孩
The girl.
她现在正在
She's out there
外面的纽约城里四处溜达
walking around New York City right now,
没准穿着一双特别可爱的靴子
probably in a pair of really cute boots
我想穿的时候 她就会借给我
that she's gonna let me borrow whenever I want
因为我们有一样的尺码
because we're the same size.
她就在那外面 泰德
She is out there, Ted.
她真的在吗 可是我都找遍了
Is she, really? Because I've looked.
我苦苦寻觅
I have looked high
希望能找到一个可以让我喜欢
and low for someone I can love
让我爱慕 让我为她做华夫饼的人
and adore and cook waffles for.
可是现在最接近的人就只有马修啊
The closest I've come is Marshall.
他确实挺喜欢你做的华夫饼的
He does love your waffles.
是肉桂的缘故啦
It's the cinnamon.
我都会加肉桂的
I add cinnamon.
她根本没在纽约
She's not in New York.
或许她会在芝加哥
Maybe she's in Chicago.
好 你现在是越说越离谱了
Okay, you are being ridiculous.
你会在这儿 在纽约城里 找到那个人
You are going to find someone here in New York
而且你会爱她 就像我爱马修一样
that you love just as much as I love Marshall.
至于你
And you,
如果你让朱迪说服你不去意大利的话 我发誓
if you let Judy talk you out of going to Italy, so help me,
我的意大利饺子将永远对你的馅料关上大门
I will never let you stuff my ravioli again.
我还是把扬声器关了吧
I'm gonna take you off speaker.
莉莉 你就放一百万个心吧
Lily, you got to relax.
我妈对意大利这事可激动了
Okay, my mom is psyched about Italy.
她一直在开玩笑说
She keeps making jokes about how she's gonna
她要跟我们一起去罗马睡沙发
come live with us in Rome and sleep on the couch
给我们做饭
and cook every meal for us
我们在那的一整年
so we never have to go to a restaurant
都不用下馆子
the whole year we're there.
这不是玩笑哦
It's not a joke.
现在不准对我说不
By not saying no to me right now,
你得保证让我跟你们去罗马才行
you are giving me your full consent for that to happen.
我得挂了
I got to go.
我要说些政治上的东西
"I'm probably saying some political stuff
以显得我很聪明
right now to sound smart."
我更喜欢傲慢自大的播客
"I'm probably referring to some snooty podcast
以显得我更聪明
to sound even smarter."
我要讲法语了
"I'm probably saying something in French."
啊
Aah!
我的天...
My God...
噢
Ow.
好了
Okay,
你想要拆散他们吗
you want to break them up?
我有一个计划
I got a plan.
这计划以前成功过
It's something I know has worked in the past,
但是 有风险
but it-it's, it's risky,
所以 现在取消还来得及
so it's, it's not too late to call it off.
不 我也参与
No way, I'm in.
很好 其实现在想取消已经来不及了
Good, 'cause it's too late to call it off.
好戏开始
Observe.
这就是为什么参议院
And that is why the senate
不能通过任何议案
can't push anything through.
道格•曼德在他的播客里也是这么说的
And Doug Mand said the same thing in his podcast.
就像是"身后之事与我何干"
It's like, "Apres moi le deluge!"
噢
Ooh.
噢 天啊
Oh, my gosh.
噢 我的天 噢 我的神
Oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh.
好 好 好
Yes, yes, yes.
我愿意
Yes!
什么
What?
我愿意
Yes!
我愿意嫁给你
I will marry you!
就算是香槟杯子里的戒指
Even though a ring in a champagne glass
这样的老套的方法 就算这是个长角阶梯型戒指
is a total cliche and this is a cushion cut.
就算我暗示过你 我想要公主方形的戒指
And how long have I been hinting that I want a princess cut?
我也愿意
But yes!
这是个误会 这戒指不是我的
That's a mistake. That's not from me.
不是你的
It's not?
我们在一起才七年而已
We've only been together seven years.
-现在清楚了 -开始了
-Now it becomes clear. -Here we go.
你想像当时承诺
You want commitment the
给我弟弟工作那样敷衍我
same way you want my brother to work for you.
很抱歉我没有在酒杯里面放戒指
I'm sorry I didn't put an engagement ring in your drink.
从你以往大口喝酒的经验来看 我很惊讶你居然发现了戒指
The way you chug booze, I'm surprised you even noticed.
那么 你什么时候走
So, when are you leaving?
婚礼后的第一天
Day after the wedding.
什么
What?
你不能错过婚礼后的第一天
You can't miss the day after the wedding.
那一天我们要不醉不归 喝含羞草鸡尾酒
That's when we sit around all hungover, drinking mimosas
然后八卦一下谁长胖了
and talking smack about who looked fat.
那相当于我的圣诞节
That's my Christmas.
你为什么这么着急要走呢
Why are you in such a rush to get out of there?
噢
Oh.
当然了
Of course.
你离开这里的原因并不是因为
You're not leaving because you think
你认为你的真命天女不在纽约
the love of your life isn't in New York.
你离开这里是因为 你觉得你的她就在那里
You're leaving because you think she is.
然而下周的这个时候
And this time next week,
她就嫁给你最好的朋友了
she'll be married to your best friend.
亲爱的
Baby!
我这里正在上演
I am in the middle
非常戏剧化的一幕
of something super dramatic here.
但是 你记住了 如果你让朱迪和我们一起去罗马
But real quick: If you let Judy come to Rome with us,
你就得另找人
you are going to have to find someone else
帮你洗衣服 做脚底按摩了
to do your laundry and massage your feet.
哦 天 她都做得到是吧
Oh, my gosh, she's going to do all that, won't she?
莉莉 你不用再这么抓狂了
Lily, you have to stop freaking out.
没有任何事情会打破我们的计划
Nothing is going to screw up the plan.
我们一定会按计划执行
We're doing this.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你 亲爱的 拜拜
I love you, baby. Bye.
你好
Hello?
请问是马修•艾瑞克森吗
Hi. Marshall Eriksen?
这里是纽约州司法委员会
I'm calling from the New York State Judiciary Committee.
你还记得 几个月前你申请了法官资格吗
Uh, you applied for a judgeship a few months ago, remember?
哦 当...当然
Uh, of... of course.
是这样的 我有个好消息
Well, I have good news.
我们现在有个紧急的席位空缺
We have a last-minute opening on the bench.
你说什么
What are you saying to me right now?
我在说 恭喜你
I'm saying congratulations.
我们希望你来做法官
We want you to be a judge.
-所以你想让我做个法官  -是的
-So, you want me to be a judge? -Yes.
-然后我还要从下一周的周二开始工作  -是的
-And I would start a week from Tuesday? -Yes.
我可不可以从下一年度的周二开始工作
Could I maybe start a year from Tuesday?
不行
No.
-一定要从下周二开始  -是的
-Got to be a week from Tuesday? -Yes.
-然后我会成为一名真正的法官  -是的
-And I'd be a real judge? -Yes.
-穿长袍的那种  -是的
-With a robe? -Yes.
-有小锤的那种  -是的
-Gavel? -Yes.
-有奇怪的南方口音那种  -不是
-Wacky Southern accent? -No.
好吧 律师先生
Now, counselor,
你完全确定你在说什么吗
are you absolutely sure?
是的
Yes.
还有我还必须在纽约做这种事情
And I have to be in New York for this?
-是的  -我可以远程通话吗
-Yes. -I can't telecommute?
不行
No.
我可以做那种疯狂的扬声器法官吗
I couldn't be the crazy speakerphone judge?
-不行  -我可以用全息图像办案吗
-No. -Could I be a hologram?
-不行  -仿生机器人呢
-No. -Animatronic robot
迪士尼乐园游乐项目之一 有会演讲的林肯总统机器人
像总统大厅里面机器人亚伯拉罕•林肯那种
like Abe Lincoln from the Hall of Presidents
我可以用操纵杆遥控那种
that I control from afar with a joystick?
不行
No.
你记不记得超人漫画里面的乔•艾尔的头
Do you remember the giant Jor-El head from Superman?
详见S8E19里Barney的投影仪
-记得  -那 我可不可以...
-Yes. -Well, what if I...?
-不行  -那有没有任何办法
-No. -Is there any way
能让我在做这项工作的同时
that I could do this
又能和我妻子搬去意大利住一年呢
and also spend the next year of my life in Italy with my wife?
没有
No.
这真是个重大决定啊
This is such a big decision.
我真的不擅长做重大决定
I-I'm not good at big decisions.
你确定你真要当法官吗
Are you sure you want to be a judge?
哇噢 我们刚刚打碎了一段长达7年的恋情
Wow. Now that we've broken up a seven-year relationship
只是因为他们占了我们的桌子
just 'cause they stole our table,
-我觉得有点...  -棒极了
-I feel kind of... -Awesome?
我打算说"欲火中烧" 但没错 也很棒
I was going to say horny, but yeah, awesome, too.
不是吧
No way.
-开玩笑吧  -什么
-Are you kidding me? -What?
哇 这是要来打架吗
Whoa. Is there going to be a fight?
好吧 那就这样
Okay, here's the play.
你负责放倒那个妞 还有那个男的 我旁观
You take the girl, and the guy and I will watch.
你们好呀 我们正想找你们呢
Hello. Just the people we want to see.
因为你们 我俩大吵了一架
We got in a pretty big fight because of you guys.
还约心理医生谈了好几个小时
We had to call our therapists after hours.
可不爽了呢
Not cool.
总而言之 这事导致了我们现在的结果
Anyway, it got us to where we are now.
我们要结婚了
We're getting married!
而且我会跟她姓
And I'm taking her last name.
你们也应该考虑这样做
You should think about doing the same thing.
-那晚安咯  -晚安
-Well, good night. -Good night.
-晚安  -恭喜你们
-Good night. -Congratulations.
是啊 必须恭喜
Yes, definitely.
是因为我们
That was us.
我们促成了这桩喜事
We made that happen.
我们太帅了
We're pretty cool.
你知道 再过一周
And, you know, a week from today,
我们就会变成一对传奇... 等一下...
we are going to be legend... wait for it...
夫妻
Married.
传奇夫妻×2
-Legend-married. -Legend-married.
罗宾•舍巴斯基 我太特么爱你了
Robin Scherbatsky, I love you so damn much.
我也爱你 巴尼•舍巴斯基
I love you, too, Barney Scherbatsky.
听上去不错
That sounds good.
-嘘  -考虑一下吧
-Shh. -Think about it.
他们很幸福
They're happy.
我也很为他们高兴
And I'm happy for them.
我希望他们共度精彩的人生 只是
I want them to have an amazing life together. I just...
我只是觉得 我不参与其中
I just think it would be best for everyone
会对所有人都好
if I wasn't around for it.
最近你跟罗宾之间发生什么事了吗
Did something happen recently between you and Robin?
没有
No.
便便埋哪儿了 泰德
Where's the poop, Ted?
S06E03出现过 罗宾和唐分手后莉莉追问罗宾的台词
那天她给我打电话
She called me up the other day.
想要挖出那个埋在中央公园
She was trying to dig up this locket
旋转木马后面的吊坠小盒
she had buried behind the Central Park Carousel,
我推掉了一场很重要的面试去帮她
and I blew off that big interview to go help her.
后来 下起了雨
And then... it started raining.
我 呃
I'll, uh...
婚礼上见
I'll see you at the wedding.
嗯
Yeah.
即使是现在 已经过了这么多年
Even now, after all these years,
我心中仍然有一个角落驱使着我
there's still just this part of me where,
就算只有最渺茫的机会
if there's even the slightest chance
能让我使罗宾展开笑颜
something I do could make Robin smile,
我都绝不多想 义无反顾
I don't even think about it-- I just do it.
我是说 如果我能让吊坠小盒
I mean, if I could make
奇迹般出现 我肯定去做
that locket magically appear, I would.
哪怕要切开我手臂上的脉络
I would open a vein in my arm
让吊坠从我的血液中流淌出来
if I could bleed that locket out,
只要能让她开心
just to make her happy.
而对方却是你最好朋友的未婚妻
That's just a really sucky way to feel
这真的再难堪不过了
about your best friend's fiancee.
所以 我会去参加婚礼
So I'm going to come to the wedding,
你知道 愉快地度过 但那之后...
you know, I'll have a good time, but after that, I...
怎么了
What?
我知道那个吊坠小盒在哪
I know where the locket is.
什么
What?
我知道那个吊坠小盒在哪
I know where the locket is.
那是几年之前
It-it was a few years ago,
就在你要和斯黛拉结婚之前
right before you were supposed to marry Stella.
2008年
有天晚上我去酒吧喝点东西
I went down to the bar one night to get a drink
然后碰见了谁呢
and what should I see?
莉莉
Lily!
嘿 小妞
Hey, girl.
问你个问题啊
I got a question for you.
泰德要娶的为什么不是我
Why isn't Ted marrying me?
噢
Whoa
对不起 哦 天哪
I'm sorry. Oh, God.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是... 我应该为他感到开心的
I just... I-I should be happy for him,
可我却是这个样子
and yet here I am,
打算搬去日本住 仅仅是为了躲开他
moving off to Japan just to get away from him.
还有大概想去看看
And-and I guess to see those...
兵马俑和长城什么的
those terra-cotta warriors and the Great Wall.
那是中国
Well, that's China.
哪个 这个吗
What? This?
不 这只是个纸盘子
No, it's just a paper plate.
china还有陶瓷的意思 罗宾以为莉莉说盘子是陶瓷的
呃 咱还是离开这儿吧
Uh, we should get out of here.
-快点 走啦  -哦 没错
-Come on. Come on. -Oh, totally.
我知道我们应该去哪
I know just where we should go.
天啊 你喝醉后行动还真是迅速
Man, you're fast when you're drunk.
不过至少你做的决定还是正确的
But at least you're still making good decisions.
中央公园 大半夜的
Central Park, around midnight,
用勺子挖洞
digging a hole with a spoon.
太靠谱了
Solid.
有啦
Jackpot.
那是个什么
What is that?
我的"旧物"
My something old.
西方习俗中婚礼必备品
这个吊坠小盒是我祖母的
This locket was my grandma's.
二战期间她一直把这个藏在自己屁股里
She kept it hidden in her butt all through World War II.
什么 她当时在哪
What? Where was she?
温尼泊
Winnipeg.
加拿大城市名
哦 拜托
Oh, come on.
莉莉 我开玩笑的啦
Lily, it's a joke.
我本来打算嫁给泰德的时候戴着它的
Yeah, I was going to wear this when I married Ted.
现在看来是没戏了
I guess that's not going to happen.
所以我要把它带去日本
So I am taking it with me to Japan.
好了莉莉 帮忙把这个吊坠小盒放到我屁股里
Okay, Lily, help me put this locket in my butt.
好了 你知道吗
Okay. Uh, you know what?
不如我们把它放在这个铅笔盒里
Why don't we put it in this pencil box instead?
哦 那我就把这个铅笔盒带去日本
Oh, and then I will take the pencil box with me to Japan.
好啦 莉莉
Okay. Hey, Lily?
帮忙把这个铅笔盒放到我屁股里
Help me put this pencil box in my butt.
等下
Wait!
我还有另一件事情要做
There's one other thing I have to do.
莉莉 这个很重要
Lily, it's very important.
这事情必须要做成
It's something that needs to happen
-刻不容缓  -啥事
-right now. -Yeah?
然后她吐了我一脸
Then she barfed in my face.
真是美好的一晚上
It was a lovely night.
等下 你把吊坠小盒放在赛车铅笔盒里了吗
Wait. You put the locket in the race car pencil box?
对 然后罗宾把它带到日本去了
Yep. And then Robin took it to Japan.
不 她没带
No, she didn't.
它现在就放在我家的写字台上
It's sitting on my desk at home right now.
它一直都在我那
It's been with me all along.
-泰德  -吊坠小盒居然在铅笔盒里
-Ted. -The locket is in the pencil box.
这太棒了
This is awesome.
泰德
Ted.
不 我是说
No, I just... I just mean,
这将是有史以来最棒的结婚礼物了
this is going to be the best wedding gift ever.
绝对会让她惊喜万分
It's going to blow her mind.
泰德
Ted.
小心点
Be careful.
周五
上午10点
\N婚礼前56小时
Simple Song by The Shins
Well this is just a simple song
这首歌平淡无常
To say what you've done
讲述你曾经的过往
I told you about all those fears
我曾将恐惧对你讲
And away they did run
它们果然就此消亡
You sure must be strong
你是那么的坚强
When you feel like an ocean being warmed by the sun
当你化身大海 沐浴温暖日光
快点 我们该走了
Come on, we got to go.
等等 我是不是忘了什么
Wait. What am I forgetting?
什么也没有 你什么都没忘 咱们走吧
Nothing. You're not forgetting anything. Let's go.
When I was just nine-years-old
当我正值九岁懵懂
哦 等等 我忘了点事儿
Oh, wait, I'm forgetting something.
什么
What?
I swear that I dreamt
我做过一个梦
-咱们去结婚吧  -好
-Let's go get married. -Yeah.
Your face on a football field
你面朝绿茵球场
And a kiss that I kept
当时本该给你的一个吻
Under my vest
却藏在衣衫下方
Apart from everything, but the heart in my chest
不偏不倚 我的心房之上
给马尔文准备起飞时咬的瓶子
Bottle for Marvin during takeoff.
知道了 宝贝
Got it, baby.
嘿 想想看
And hey, just think,
从现在开始一周以后
one week from right now...
我们就在意大利了
We'll be in Italy.
好了 呃 我得挂了 亲爱的
Okay, um, I-I got to go, baby.
我爱你
Um, I love you.
你还没告诉她呢
You still haven't told her.
没有
No.
这是个当面说的消息
This is face-to-face news.
祝你好运
Good luck with that...
法官大人
Your Honor.
Don't go thinking you gotta be tough
不要觉得你必须做到坚强
and play like a stone
像顽石那样抵抗
哈啰
Hello.
Could be there's nothing else in our lives
也许生命中不会有第二个地方
as this little home
像这个小家一样
-你需要我帮你提[抓]一下包[蛋]吗  -是的 谢谢
-You want me to grab your bag? -Yeah. Thanks.
嘿 我不想在婚礼分散大家的注意力 所以
Hey, I don't want to draw focus from the wedding, so...
芝加哥的事不要告诉任何人
don't tell anyone about Chicago.
那是个大城市 有一堆体育队伍
It's a major city with a bunch of sports teams
还有好吃的匹萨
and some pretty good pizza.
我觉得人们都知道芝加哥
I think people know about Chicago.
你周一几点走
What time do you leave on Monday?
一大早
Early.
周日晚上就得回城
Gonna have to head back to the city Sunday night.
那你要怎么回来
How are you going to get back?
大概坐火车吧
Guess I'll take the train.
Well is just a simple song
这首歌平淡无常
To say what you've done
讲述你曾经的过往
I told you about all those fears
我曾将恐惧对你讲
And away they did run
它们果然就此消亡
You sure must be strong
你是那么的坚强
You feel like an ocean being warmed by the sun
当你化身大海 沐浴温暖日光
Remember walking a mile to your house
别忘了你家就在不远的前方
A glow in the dark
黑暗中微微发出亮光
I made a fumbling play for your heart
为了你能暗许芳心 我百出洋相
And the act struck a spark
表演中闪出一道明亮
You wore a charm on the chain
我窃来护符做成项链
That I stole especial for you
只为你一人戴上
Love's such a delicate thing that we do
我们的爱 如此珍贵如此精致
With nothing to prove
不需要任何证明
Which I never knew.
我却现在才明白
你好 请给我一张去远汉普顿的车票
Hi. One ticket to Farhampton, please.
HIMYM字幕组 谢谢观看
第八季完结 期待最终季
第九季将于九月回归 HIMYM字幕组与您共同期待
\N
\N更多周边资源及全九季典藏版 欢迎关注官方微博及人人网主页
@HIMYM字幕组